<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Stigatle.no</title>
    <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Stigatle.no</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Stig Atle Steffensen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 11:58:40 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stigatle.no/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Current status on things</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/21.10.2023.currentstatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 11:58:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/21.10.2023.currentstatus/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to post a bit about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing currently. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my blog. Not sure if anyone reads it anyways, but I like to sit down and write a bit every once in a while..
First - I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to replace Twitter\X with something else, so I looked around for activitypub software that I could host by my self, and I then found Snac2 - https://codeberg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to NixOS</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-06-01-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:02:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-06-01-nixos/</guid>
      <description>Some days ago I wanted to try to build Yarn Desktop Client on NixOS. I installed the latest version, got some basic things set up, I then cloned my repo and instantly regretted installing NixOS, because I did not get it to work as easy as I thought. I then put my laptop away for the rest of the evening. I picked it up again the next day, determined to give it another try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yarn Desktop Client</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-03-yarn-desktop-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 18:15:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-03-yarn-desktop-client/</guid>
      <description>I felt that I needed a new &amp;lsquo;home&amp;rsquo; for social media when I shut down gnusocial \ diaspora instances I was running. I spent some time looking around. I have to admit I do not like the whole &amp;lsquo;web3&amp;rsquo; stuff (nostr for example) and others, mostly because it attracts so many cryptobro&amp;rsquo;s, and I get tired of the constant shilling they do. I do not mind crypto - I use it a lot my self, but I do not need to be reminded about it on almost every post I see on social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vps</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-02-vps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 20:18:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-02-vps/</guid>
      <description>Decided to write a bit about how things are going, I have not written much lately, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to change that. Over Christmas my VPS provider had some hardware issues - that caused the VM to become unrecoverable. I honestly did not mind - since I had backup of everything I needed, and the current VPS I had was running a really old debian version. Also it was a pain to keep things updated, since it was set up a long time ago, so after the VPS provider installed a new fresh VM for me - I then sat down to think about how I wanted to have things in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Husky</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-02-husky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 20:10:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2023-07-02-husky/</guid>
      <description>One bigger thing that happened last year in April was that we got a new dog! A alaskan husky, he was 8 weeks when we got him, broght our kids to get him, we drove about 4 hours one way to pick him up. The lady we got him from lived in a cabin in the woods, down a ski trail, her whole place was fenced in, and we walked up there, opened the gate, and got greated by about 5-6 huge huskys, and the puppies in the pen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebooting the website</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2022-11-11-migrated-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 20:27:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2022-11-11-migrated-site/</guid>
      <description>Decided to reboot my website, start fresh. I wanted to get rid of wordpress - and now I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
