<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blender on Stigatle.no</title>
    <link>https://stigatle.no/categories/blender/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blender on Stigatle.no</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Stig Atle Steffensen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 20:32:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stigatle.no/categories/blender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First patreon content has been posted.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2019-09-03-first-patreon-content-has-been-posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 20:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2019-09-03-first-patreon-content-has-been-posted/</guid>
      <description>I have posted 3 videos on patreon, this covers the compilation of pbrt on windows and linux, and also gives a quick overview of how to install the exporter and how to use it.
You get access here: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender PBRT exporter test scene.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-07-22-blender-pbrt-exporter-test-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 16:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-07-22-blender-pbrt-exporter-test-scene/</guid>
      <description>I got contacted on twitter by @Cao_Jiayin{.ProfileHeaderCard-screennameLink.u-linkComplex.js-nav} on twitter today, and he asked about a scene that I had posted previously, specifically the ‘glass monkey’ scene.

I have now re-created that scene, and exported it, zipped it, uploaded it so that you can render it out if you want to test a bit. You have to adjust ‘”integer pixelsamples” [32]’ to something much higher if you want a clean render.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status and info on my PBRT exporter for blender.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-04-26-status-and-info-on-my-pbrt-exporter-for-blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 19:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-04-26-status-and-info-on-my-pbrt-exporter-for-blender/</guid>
      <description>I want to write a bit about my first blender development project, if you follow me on twitter then you probaly already know its a renderer exporter for PBRT render engine.
You find the source code and samples scenes here:
https://github.com/stig-atle/io_scene_pbrtThe reason why I wrote it as an exporter is because it was the easiest way to get started. The project started when I decided to stop using 3dsmax and go to blender full-time, so I needed to learn everything I needed about blenders C/Python API while making this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to blender on all personal projects.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-02-11-switching-to-blender-on-all-personal-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 10:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2018-02-11-switching-to-blender-on-all-personal-projects/</guid>
      <description>So, in December (2017) I decided to leave 3dsmax and switch to blender full time for all personal work. I’ve been using 3dsmax for half my life, and still use it at work (our whole workflow there is based around autodesk software), byt at home it enabled me to completely ditch window which has been a goal of mine for a long time, it was only 3dsmax holding me back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing CentOS 7 as desktop \ developer OS.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-07-10-centos-7-as-my-main-desktop-developer-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 20:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-07-10-centos-7-as-my-main-desktop-developer-os/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I decided to give CentOS 7a try as my main OS,
the reason why is because it’s the closest you get to redhat without paying,
and I’ve been running everything from Debian to Arch, gentoo and others, but now I wanted a rock solid OS that feels predictable,
CentOS feels like the natural choice for that kind of system.
What worried me a bit was outdated software, that has been a issue before with other OS’es,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My render exporter \ integration project</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-06-16-my-render-exporter-integration-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 19:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-06-16-my-render-exporter-integration-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new project</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-06-07-my-new-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 16:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2017-06-07-my-new-project/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking about it for a long while, and now I’ve decided to invest all my free time into it.
I will integrate a renderer with Blender, first as a exporter for the file formats that the renderer uses, then
do a better integration later on when that is feature complete.
I have ditched windows completely, and with that 3dsmax. I still use 3dsmax at work every day,
but now I do not use it for anything at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing blender by compiling from source</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-08-21-customizing-blender-by-compiling-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 16:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-08-21-customizing-blender-by-compiling-from-source/</guid>
      <description>There is one small issue in blenderthat I’ve really disliked, and that is the rounded corners on every GUI item.
I absolutely hate rounded corners, I like it straight and flat.
So today I hunted it down in the source code and fixed it, that’s the beauty of open source fix it yourself.
You can see the difference in the screen shot here :
Left side is the rounded corners, right side is the GUI with my fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender   wireframe on shaded</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-08-10-blender-wireframe-on-shaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 10:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-08-10-blender-wireframe-on-shaded/</guid>
      <description>There is one thing I really missed when switching from 3dsmax to blender, and that was wire-frame on shaded view-port mode.
This is one feature I used in 3dsmax all the time, for blender you can get the same by installing this script:
http://www.pasteall.org/57345/pythonIf you are new to installing scripts, then create a file, for example ‘wireshaded.py’, then copy the text and paste it in there, make sure the indentation is correct, then go to blender’s settings\addons window, select .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning blender properly</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-05-04-learning-blender-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-05-04-learning-blender-properly/</guid>
      <description>After 16 years of 3dsmax every single day I’ve started to force my self to work in blender on my own personal projects.
At work I still use 3dsmax daily, but I’ve always had an eye for blender.
The biggest reason why I find blender so intriguing is because it’s open source and free, and also it enables me to work in my favorite OS Debian.
If something is ‘wrong’ in blender I can fix it, if I need a tool I can easily add it any way I like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making my next plugin a blender plugin.</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-03-25-making-my-next-plugin-a-blender-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 20:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2016-03-25-making-my-next-plugin-a-blender-plugin/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking a lot lately, and I’ve been thinking about starting a new project that I can do for my self that is not related to Luxrender\LuxMax.
I won’t say exactly what it is yet but it’s a new plugin.
The thing I’ve been thinking of is if I should make it for 3dsmax or blender, and I’ve decided to get more into blender now.
And I want to make my next project for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender plugin   Hard ops</title>
      <link>https://stigatle.no/posts/2015-12-20-blender-plugin-hard-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stigatle.no/posts/2015-12-20-blender-plugin-hard-ops/</guid>
      <description>It’s no secret that I’m a huge fan of open source tools.
I’ve been using Blenderfor a good while, I try to use it more and more in my own projects.
The reason why I love blender is because it’s open source, and cross-platform.
If there is a issue I can go in and fix it myself, and also it has very powerful features.
At work I do not get to use it, because we’re all on the Autodesk product line, so all the in-house tools I’ve made is for 3dsmax only.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
